创世之初 冥冥之中
In the beginning, there was darkness...
随着轰的一声
and then, bang...
诞生了无限膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence...
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
现在 所见超乎我们的想象
Now, see further than we've ever imagined...
超越了我们生存的限制
beyond the limits of our existence...
这个空间我们称之为"宇宙"
in a place we call "The Universe."
听起来宛如好莱坞大片:
It sounds like a Hollywood blockbuster:
一颗致命小行星正在撞向地球
a deadly asteroid is on a collision course with Earth.
但是在现实中 真有一颗巨大的世界末日大石头
But in reality, is there a giant doomsday rock...
威胁着要抹去文明吗?
that threatens to wipe out civilization?
不是会不会发生的问题
It's not a question of if it'll happen.
而是何时会发生的问题
It's a question of when it will happen.
小行星在6500万年前抹去了恐龙
An asteroid took out the dinosaurs 65 million years ago.
下来轮到我们了吗?
Are we next?
着手搜索这些宇宙杀手
Go in search of these cosmic killers...
评估它们的威胁
assess their threat...
分析最佳方法 在它们遭遇我们之前去截获它们
and analyze the best ways to get them before they get us.
《阻止世界末日》从现在抓起
"Stopping Armageddon" starts now.
宇宙:阻止世界末日
它来自火星和木星之间的小行星带的某个地方
It came from somewhere in the asteroid belt...between Mars and Jupiter...
一大堆碎石翻滚着
a massive pile of rock and rubble...
大摇大摆一路奔向地球
rotating and rumbling its way towards Earth.
昔日大爆炸所产生的残骸
What was once mere debris from the Big Bang...
现在注定要制造其自身的大爆炸
is now destined to make a big bang of its own.
突然闯入地球的大气层
Bursting through the Earth's atmosphere...
这个巨大的小行星会变成不可阻挡的力量
this giant asteroid becomes an unstoppable force.
其威力是苏联的"帝王核弹"的200万倍
Nearly two million times more powerful...than the Soviet "Emperor Bomb"...
那是史上引爆过的规模和威力最大的核装置
the largest, most powerful explosive device ever detonated.
它的目标是 洛杉矶
Its target? Los Angeles.
人们最后一眼看到的是火光
The last thing anyone there sees is a flash...
火球
a fireball...
然后...
and then...
如果这颗小行星如我们设想的大如
lf this asteroid were as large as we might imagine...
直径10公里的小行星
a 10-kilometer asteroid...
我们认为撞击坑将会大上10倍
we would be talking about a crater that is ten times larger than that...
我们认为会有50英里的撞击坑
so we'd be talking about a 50-mile crater.
因此整个洛杉矶将最终会变成这巨大的陨石坑
So all of Los Angeles would end up being this humongous crater.
我们认为绝对是毁灭性的
We'd be talking about absolute devastation...
100英里范围内的东西将荡然无存
nothing left over a range up to perhaps 100 miles.
远处的圣地亚哥 都会感到有强烈的地震
As far away as San Diego, they would get massive Earthquakes.
都会受到巨大的气浪冲击
They would get massive air blasts.
狂风荡平200英里外的一切
Winds that would simply flatten everything 200 miles away...
将会伤及1000英里范围内的一切
would kill everything out to a range of perhaps 1,000 miles.
那还只是直接的影响
And that's just the immediate impact.
随后你会看到整个碎片坠落回地球
Then you would have all this debris fall back on the planet Earth.
将会像圣诞树那样
It'd be like a Christmas tree...
看到所有的装饰品向四面八方抛洒出来
seeing all these ornaments being thrown out in all directions.
于是你会看到大爆发
And then you would see firestorms...
大地熊熊燃烧
enormous areas of the planet Earth burning...
释放出大量的烟尘
releasing even more soot and ash in the air...
遮天蔽日
blanketing out sunlight.
温度骤降
Temperatures would then plunge...
生命将会被消灭
and life itself would be perhaps extinguished.
你所看到的是严重的地球撞击事件的最坏的情景
What you've just seen is a worst-case scenario...of a major Earth impact event.
可以消灭大部分地球生命
The kinds of asteroids that can extinguish much of the life on Earth...
大部分物种的各种小行星
most of the species...
约每一亿年左右光顾一次
come around every, say, hundred million years or so.
它不是周期性现象
And it's not a periodic phenomenon.
并不会每一亿年发生一次
It doesn't happen every hundred million years.
它随时都会发生
It could happen at any time.
只是平均起来 大约每一亿年一次
Just on average, roughly once every hundred million years.
因此不是会不会发生的问题
So it's not a question of if it'll happen.
而是何时发生的问题
It's a question of when it will happen.
小行星和彗星一直在撞击地球
Asteroids and comets have been crashing into the Earth...
只要存在着地球
for as long as there's been an Earth.
在诞生后不久
Soon after its formation...
约四 五十亿年前
about four and a half billion years ago...
我们的星球就成为了宇宙射击场里被频繁光顾的目标
our planet became a frequent target in a cosmic shooting gallery.
小行星和彗星为早期的地球带来了
Asteroids and comets brought to the early Earth...
大部分的有机物质和水
much of the organic materials and water...
让生命得以形成
that allowed life to form.
后来的撞击
Subsequent collisions...
像6500万年前抹去恐龙的那一个
like the one that took out the dinosaurs 65 million years ago...
打断了演化
punctuated evolution...
让最具适应力的物种 那就是我们
allowing the most adaptable species-- that's us--
登上了食物链的顶端
to rise to the top of the food chain.
因此 我们应当将我们的存在和处境
So we owe our very existence and our position...
归功于有时会造成威胁的那些物体
to these objects that sometimes cause a threat.
根据地球撞击数据库
According to the Earth Impact Database...
有160多个陨石坑得到了证实
more than 160 impact craters have been identified.
最大的叫做希克苏鲁伯
The largest one is called Chicxulub...
玛雅语中的"魔鬼的尾巴"
Mayan for "tail of the devil."
这个陨石坑的直径超过了110英里
This crater measures more than 110 miles in diameter.
它就是消灭恐龙的那颗小行星造成的
It was made by the asteroid that took out the dinosaurs...
当时它坠落在墨西哥的尤卡坦半岛外
when it crashed off Mexico's Yucatan Peninsula.
就在家门口 数据库里
Closer to home, the database also includes...
还有亚利桑那州北部的陨石坑
Meteor Crater in northern Arizona.
现在作为旅游景点 这个1公里宽的大坑
Now a tourist attraction, this kilometer-wide hole...
是一块巨大的宇宙铁矿石留下的
was left by a huge chunk of cosmic iron ore...
它在5万年前撞上了地球
that collided with Earth about 50,000 years ago.
就在不久前
Much more recently...
一块巨大的近地物体并没有留下陨石坑
an enormous near-Earth object didn't leave a crater...
但还是造成了相当大的影响
but still made quite an impression.
携带1500万吨核弹当量
Packing the energy of a 15-megaton bomb...
超过了广岛投下的原子弹的1000倍
more than 1,000 times that of the one dropped on Hiroshima...
1908年在西伯利亚通古斯爆炸
it exploded over Tunguska, Siberia, in 1908.
它甚至
It didn't even hit the ground.
并没有击中地面
But the shock wave from this air burst...
将这个区域里所有的树木与植被夷为平地
flattened all the trees and vegetation in the area.
就像是一只巨手从天而降
It was like a gigantic hand that came down from the heavens...
推到了所有的林木
to press all the forests and trees.
那就是通古斯破坏的规模
That's the size of the devastation of Tunguska.
要是通古斯事件发生在莫斯科
If the Tunguska event had occurred over Moscow...
或纽约 洛杉矶
or New York or Los Angeles...
破坏将是灾难性的
the devastation would have been catastrophic...
会彻底摧毁城市及其周围大片区域
completely destroying the city and a vast area around it.
尽管通古斯之类的事件的再次遭遇
Though the chances of a Tunguska-type event...
遥遥无期 有可能每500年遭遇一次
happening again are remote, perhaps once every 500 years...
但是重大灾难发生的可能性是不容忽视的
the potential for a major disaster, if it does occur, can't be ignored.
那就是航天局在喷气推进实验室
That's why NASA established the Near-Earth Object program...
设立近地物体项目的原因所在
at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory.
其任务就是发现
Its mission is to find asteroids...
对地球构成最严重威胁的小行星
that pose the most serious threats to Earth...
第一步就是阻止世界末日
the first step in stopping Armageddon.
2032年是一颗0.02的
2032 is a .O2.
这些不太正常 这是颗0.01的
- These are just anomalous. - There's a .01.
要问我近地物体项目中
Whenever I'm asked what are the most important aspects...
最重要的方面
of the Near-Earth Object program...
我会说 有三个最重要的方面
I say, well, the three most important aspects...
就是早发现 早发现
are find them early, find them early...
还是早发现
and then find them early.
因为如果我们能发现它们
Because if we can find them...
在问题产生之前10年 20年 30年
10, 20, 30 years in advance of a problem...
我们可以用现在的技术去减缓它们
we have the technology now to mitigate them.
近地物体项目(NEO)调用五架全天候的望远镜
The N.E.O. program employs five full-time telescopes...
它们坐落于美国西南部和世界各地
located across the American southwest and around the world.
它们搜索天空 寻找小行星
They search the skies for asteroids...
尤其是那些直径至少1公里的家伙
especially those measuring at least one kilometer in diameter...
也就是约三分之二英里以及更大
or about two-thirds of a mile and larger.
那样大的小行星的撞击会造成全球性灾难
Asteroids that big can cause worldwide devastation on impact.
我们来对比一下发现小行星的方法与
We can compare the process of finding asteroids...
计算高尔夫球
to the process of figuring out...
击出后落于何地的方法
where a golf ball is going to land after it's been hit.
现在就来想象一下 并不要能看到
Now just imagine that instead of being able...
高尔夫球的整个飞行路径
to see the golf ball continuously throughout its entire flight...
而是我只要能看到其飞行过程中的少数定格的快照
I only have a handful of freeze-frame snapshots of it while it's moving.
现在我就可以计算出它会跑向何处
And now I've got to figure out where it's going to go.
因此 首先 我要正确地将照片里的
So, first of all, I've got to correctly distinguish...
高尔夫球与其它物体区分开来
the golf ball in the frame from all other objects in the frame...
比如那些树啊 鸟啊
say trees or birds...
甚至并非同一个球的其它高尔夫球
or even other golf balls that may not be the same one.
一旦我确定了每一幅照片里的高尔夫球
Once I've identified the golf ball in each of the frames...
我就需要利用万有引力定律知识
I need to use what I know about the laws of gravity...
来正确地匹配它的轨迹
to correctly fit a trajectory to it...
这样我就可以计算出它最终的落地点
so that I can figure out where it finally lands.
同样之理 我们寻找小行星时
In the same way, when we look for asteroids...
我们也就摄取天空各个区域的快照
we have to just take snapshots of different parts of the sky...
将小行星区分于星星 星系
and distinguish the asteroid from stars, from galaxies...
其它任何的暂时现象
and from any other transient phenomenon...
比如说宇宙射线
like, say, cosmic rays.
然后我们要利用万有引力定律
Then we have to use the laws of gravity...
来匹配它的模型轨道
to fit a model orbit to it...
计算出它最终到达的地方
and figure out where it's actually going to go in the end.
NEO项目的望远镜所发现的小行星
No telescopes in the N.E.O. program have found more asteroids...
并没有超过林肯近地小行星研究中心
than those at Lincoln Near-Earth Asteroid Research...
简称 LINEAR
LINEAR for short.
位于新墨西哥州南部
Located in southern New Mexico...
他们已经发现了5000颗已知的近地小行星中的近一半
they've discovered almost half of the 5,000 known near-Earth asteroids...
包括700个直径1公里
including about half of the 700 objects...
或更大的物体中的一半
measuring one kilometer or larger.
我们在LINEAR项目中用于搜寻小行星的
One of the telescopes we use for hunting for asteroids...
一架望远镜就在我的身后
with the LINEAR program is behind me.
它实际上按照天文学标准
This is actually not a rather large telescope...
并不是一架相对较大的望远镜
by astronomical standards.
其孔径就一米
It's one meter in aperture.
然而其灵敏度的秘密
But the secret to its sensitivity...
就在于那个蓝片 你可以看到
is that blue square that you can see...
就在望远镜的底部
down in the bottom of the telescope.
那是一个电荷耦合元件(CCD)
That's a charge-coupled device...
专门用于广域传感搜索
specially manufactured for wide area-sensitive search.
这台望远镜与那个CCD相结合
The combination of this telescope and that CCD...
所提供的系统的灵敏度
gives us a system exceeding one million times the sensitivity...
是人眼的1百万倍
of the human eye.
这就是 LINEAR望远镜所看到的天空的模样
This is what the sky looks like through the LINEAR telescope.
你可以看到若干恒星固定不动
What you can see is a number of stars here that are fixed.
同时 在那个数据里 还有若干近地物体
And also, in that data, there are a number of near-Earth objects.
现在我们要做的就是处理这些数据
What I'm going to do now is have the process the data...
分析找出移动的物体
and analyze it to find the moving objects.
做法就是点击五幅快照
What it's doing is it's clicking through the five frames...
事实上 现在就已经发现了若干移动的物体
and, in fact, has now discovered a number of moving objects.
你现在看到的比如这个
What you see here are ones that look like this.
这些实际上是主带小行星
These are actually main belt asteroids.
它们就位于火星和木星之间的小行星带里
They're out located in the main belt between Mars and Jupiter.
它们并不构成任何威胁
They don't pose any threat at all.
而在另一方面 你可以发现有两个非常异样
On the other hand, you find a couple of them that are very different.
这个 事实上 在主带逆向移动
This one's, in fact, going opposite motion...
速度非常快
of the main belt, and much, much faster.
这个在笔直前行
This one's going straight across.
这些事实上就是近地物体
These are, in fact, near-Earth objects.
事实上 这两个就是LINEAR发现的
And, in fact, these are two that LINEAR discovered.
LINEAR将数据发送到
LINEAR sends its data...
马萨诸塞州剑桥国际小行星组织
to the Minor Planet Center in Cambridge, Massachusetts...
那是所有发现的近地物体的信息交流中心
the clearinghouse for all near-Earth object searches.
国际小行星组织的具体工作
The Minor Planet Center's job specifically...
就是将新近地物体的观察
is to tie the observations of new N.E.O.s
与已存在的近地物体联系起来
with already existing N.E.O.s...
然后精炼出近地物体总体的轨道
and just refine the orbits of the near-Earth objects in general.
利用这些轨道
With the orbits...
其他组织就可以进行物理观察
other groups can go perform physical observations...
利用各种望远镜来确定物体的实际大小
using various telescopes to determine the actual sizes of the objects.
国际小行星组织认为小行星具有潜在的危险
The Minor Planet Center considers an asteroid potentially hazardous...
前提就在其轨道将其带到了距地球500万英里的范围内
if its orbit brings it to within five million miles of Earth.
那对宇宙的舒适度来说太近了
That's too close for cosmic comfort...
肯定上了杜林灾难指数的一个等级
and definitely earns a rating on the Torino Scale...
那是一个指南 科学家用来评估 小行星所构成威胁的等级
a guide scientists use to assess the threat level posed by an asteroid.
该等级从0到10
The scale ranges from zero to ten...
10是完全毁灭 0代表没有任何风险
where ten is absolute destruction and zero means no hazard at all...
或极少会遭遇任何的撞击
or very little chance of any sort of impact.
迄今已经录入杜林灾难指数最高等级的物体
The highest rating that any object has ever received so far...
是一颗小行星 叫做阿波菲斯
on the Torino Scale was an asteroid called Apophis.
阿波菲斯的名字来自埃及的毁灭之神
And Apophis is named after the Egyptian god of destruction.
阿波菲斯一度到达了杜林灾难指数四级
Apophis, at one point, had a Torino rating as high as four.
事实上 在2004年12月发现后的几个星期里
In fact, in the weeks following its discovery in December 2004...
曾有一个时段 它表现出
there was a time period when it appeared to have...
在2029年会有2.7%的撞击概率
as high as 2.7 percent chance of impact in 2029.
那是约1: 37
That's about one in 37.
那是轮盘赌的赔率 而不是乐透彩的赔率
These are roulette odds, not lottery odds.
因此在当时 大家都开始
And so, at that time, everybody really started...
密切关注阿波菲斯在2029年潜在威胁了
paying a close attention to Apophis as a possible threat in 2029.
实际长约270米
Measuring about 270 meters in length...
即800英尺多一点
or more than 800 feet...
阿波菲斯具有500个百万吨级的当量
Apophis has the energy of a 500-Megaton bomb...
足以抹平一个大都市 或造成毁灭性的海啸
enough to wipe out a major city or cause a devastating tsunami.
到了2029年 阿波菲斯距离地球
In 2029, Apophis will come closer to the Earth...
将比转播这个电视节目的卫星更近
than the satellite bringing you this TV program.
尽管超常地靠近 额外的雷达和光学分析
Despite the unusual proximity, additional radar and optical analysis...
已经排除了对地球撞击的威胁
have eliminated the threat of an Earth impact...
杜林灾难指数零级
a zero on the Torino Scale.
但是在那个轨道上 阿波菲斯有可能穿越一个钥匙孔
But during that orbit, Apophis may pass through a keyhole...
太空里的一个区域 如果有小行星穿越那里
an area in space where, if the asteroid passes through it...
就会有4.5万分之一的概率
there's a one in 45,000 chance...
在2036年与地球有另一次遭遇
of another encounter with Earth in 2036.
2036年里发生撞击的可能性
The possibility of a collision in 2036...
是我们要认真监视的情况
is something that we're very carefully monitoring.
然而 我们观察阿波菲斯的极佳的机会
And yet, we have excellent opportunities...
是在2013年前后
to observe Apophis in around the year 2013...
还有2021年前后
and again around the year 2021.
届时 我们就可以有充分的信心称
At which time, with very high confidence...
撞击的可能性将被排除
we can say that that possibility of impact will be eliminated.
不太可能的情况 就是撞击的可能性依然存在的话
In the unlikely case that that possibility of impact persists...
我们还会有充分的时间来规避撞击
we will still have plenty of time to avert the collision...
通过某种缓解的行动
through some kind of a mitigation campaign.
缓解是阻止世界末日的下一步
Mitigation is the next step to stopping Armageddon.
如何来预防阿波菲斯以及其它大型小行星
How do we prevent Apophis or any large asteroid...
撞击地球造成大规模破坏呢?
from colliding into Earth and causing mass devastation?
显然答案有可能是最差劲的选择
The obvious answer may be the worst option of all.
我们的幸存取决于对这个问题的回答:
Our very survival depends on the answer to this question:
一旦我们发现有较大的小行星 处于撞击地球的轨道上
if we find a large asteroid on track to collide with Earth...
我们能够采取行动来预防它的发生吗?
can we do anything to prevent it from happening?
你可以将小行星撞击视为巨大的自然灾难
You can think of an asteroid impact as a huge natural disaster.
但是问题是它不同于
But the thing that makes this different...
我们已知的各种自然灾难
than the kinds of natural disasters that we know about--
飓风 地震 诸如此类的东西
hurricanes or earthquakes or things like that--
那些原则上是可以预防的
is that, in principle, it's preventable.
因此你的工作未必就是如何去善后
So your job isn't necessarily how do you clean up in the aftermath...
而是如何去预防它
but how do you prevent it...
那是一个重大的区别
and that's an important distinction.
预防大规模的地球撞击
Preventing a massive Earth impact...
把我们带到了阻止世界末日的第二步:
brings us to step two for stopping Armageddon:
缓解
mitigation.
让致命的近地物体失效谈何容易
Neutralizing a deadly near-Earth object is no easy task.
它来自好莱坞
Take it from Hollywood.
亦或不行
Or maybe not.
最糟糕的做法尽在好莱坞电影里
The worst thing to do is to look at all the Hollywood movies...
我们看到猛男走出航天飞机
where we have macho men going out in the space shuttle...
来到深太空 将氢弹放到那些物体上
way out in deep space, planting hydrogen bombs on these objects.
嗯 首先 航天飞机甚至都到不了那个距离
Well, first of all, the space shuttle can't even reach those distances.
航天飞机只能够围绕着地球本身运转
The space shuttle simply goes around the planet Earth itself.
其次 更重要的是
Second of all, and more important...
炸毁小行星是最糟糕的方案
to blow up an asteroid is the worst possible scenario.
因为没有了一颗大型小行星
'Cause instead of having one monster asteroid...
你现在则有了两个 三个 或四个碎片
you now have two, three, four pieces...
每一块都足以对地球发起巨大的撞击
each piece capable of initiating tremendous havoc on the planet Earth.
另一方面 如果它是个大型物体
On the other hand, if it were a large object...
你就有足够的时间 若干年的时间
and you had enough time, several years...
你可以尝试去炸毁它
you could try and blow it up...
希望弹片能避开地球
and hope that the shrapnel would miss the Earth...
至少大部分能避开
or most of it would.
不过对于大物体 我们几乎能提前发现的
But large objects we almost certainly would find ahead of time.
实际上众多小物体
It's really the small, far more numerous objects...
才是难以对付的
that are the ones that are tough to deal with.
如果彻底摧毁
If outright destruction...
如好莱坞式的炸毁 太冒险了
such as a Hollywood-style bombing, is too risky...
或者充其量 只保留最大的小行星
or, at best, reserved for only for the largest asteroids...
更为保险的
there's a safer way...
就是将近地物体移出危害的路径
to move a near-Earth object out of harm's way...
那就是偏离
and that's by deflection.
如果小行星一头撞向地球
lf an asteroid is headed toward an impact with Earth...
你最好是极其轻微地改变其轨道
you're far better off by changing its orbit very slightly...
这样让它避开地球 呆在一个地方
so that it misses the Earth, but stays in one piece...
要好过你试图炸毁它
much better off than you are trying to break it up.
你无法让任何物体消失殆尽
You can't make anything disappear.
你只能将它炸成碎片
You simply break it into pieces.
轰炸它将会将它炸成碎片
Bombing it is going to break it into pieces...
将会造成更多的破坏
which could do much more damage.
那会是霰弹攻击来代替步枪子弹
It's a shotgun blast instead of a rifle bullet.
要效果最佳 偏离则需要尽可能的提前量
To work best, deflection requires as much lead time as possible.
数年 甚至数十年
Years, if not decades.
简而言之 早发现意味着早偏离
Put simply, early detection means early deflection.
尤为重要的是 它越远
More importantly, the farther away it is...
我们所要施加的力量就越小
the less force we have to apply...
以导致小行星轨道的大转移
in order to cause a large shift in the asteroid's orbit.
为了证明这一点 我们来玩一下冰球
To demonstrate the point, let's play hockey.
球员击球距离球门越远
The further away from the net a player shoots the puck...
阻挡目标所需的偏离也就越小
the less deflection will be needed to prevent a goal.
然而 如果球员射门越靠近球门
However, if a player takes a shot much closer to the net...
那么就需要更大的偏离
then a much larger deflection is required...
让冰球转向
to keep the puck from going in.
现在来设想一下 那冰球是颗小行星
Now imagine that the puck is an asteroid...
球门是地球
and the net is the Earth.
首选方案
The preferred scenarios...
就是通过改变其速度来偏离小行星
are to deflect the asteroid by changing its velocity.
如果我们进行偏离有足够的提前量
lf we can do that sufficiently far in advance...
比方说 10年
for example, ten years...
我们就只需要改变其速度不足每秒一厘米
we only need to change its velocity less than one centimeter per second.
因此这是速度上的极其微小的改变
So it's a very, very small change in velocity.
于是其累积效应将意味着
The cumulative effect then will mean...
它将会抵达的地方 既不是在我们的前方
that it will get to where we are either before we are there...
或地球所处位置的后方
or after the Earth is at that position...
因此将不再是个问题了
so it is no longer a problem.
要做到这一点 几个偏转策略已经提出
To do just that, several deflection strategies have been proposed.
要说声对不起布鲁斯.威利斯了
And with apologies to Bruce Willis...
丝毫不需要载人飞行
none requires a manned mission.
事实上 载人飞行将极大地妨碍那些东西
In fact, a manned mission would significantly hinder these things.
对此 利用目前的技术和目前的航天器
To this point, with current technology and current vehicles...
我们实际上无法跑得离地球很远
we can't really get very far away from the Earth...
那将严重制约你的能力
and that severely constrains your ability...
去真正解决其中的一个问题
to actually solve one of these problems...
如果最佳时间可能是到太阳的对面
when the optimal time might be the opposite side of the Sun...
去造访小行星
to meet the asteroid.
法国研究人员提出的一个偏离策略
One deflection strategy advanced by French researchers...
叫做征用无威胁的小行星
calls for commandeering a non-threatening asteroid...
将近地物体敲离轨道
to knock an Earth-bound object off course.
这个策略可谓是"以星制星"
Call this strategy "asteroid versus asteroid."
它并非是天方夜谭
It's not totally outside the realm of possibility.
尝试将它停泊在我们想要的地方
Trying to park it where we want it...
不让它撞击地球是问题的要害
and not have it hit the Earth is in itself questionable.
我们只有其中的某些处在地球的附近
We have only a certain number of these...that are anywhere near the Earth.
发现有小行星活动在地球附近
And finding one that could be easily moved...
显然 你要考虑到同样是小行星
in near Earth, obviously, you're talking about the same asteroids...
有可能会有撞击地球的危险
that might be in danger of hitting the Earth to start with.
因此我是不会赞成考虑
And so I would not be in favor of thinking...
取上一个以做备用
of bringing one in to have it later.
今后要打击较大小行星是非常困难的
And the ability to shoot a large asteroid later is very difficult.
我们不需要大物体
We don't need something that large...
具有足够的能量和动力来偏离它
to have enough energy and momentum to deflect it.
另一项提案出自欧洲航天局
Another proposal comes from the European Space Agency.
它所筹划的任务叫做堂吉诃德
It's preparing designs for a mission name Don Quixote.
不是用倾斜的风车
Instead of tilting at windmills...
该机构计划改变无威胁小行星的方向
the agency plans to alter the course of a non-threatening asteroid...
利用发射所谓的动能撞击器的航天器
by launching a spacecraft, called a kinetic impactor...
去撞击它
to collide into it.
动能撞击器是我准备的工具箱里的重头戏
A kinetic impactor's number one in my toolbox of what l would do.
非常简单 直截了当
It's very simple, it's straightforward...
我们至少有了一条底线
and we at least have a bottom line...
我们知道我们可以依赖的最低限度
a minimum effect that we know we can count on.
我们可以发射足够大的东西
We can launch something large enough...
以足够大的速度 在至少 比方说10年 20年里
at sufficiently high velocity within at least, let's say, 10 years, 20 years...
将一颗小行星偏移数百米的范围
to deflect an asteroid up into the several hundred meter range.
动能撞击 以及以星制星的策略
Kinetic impact and asteroid versus asteroid strategies...
都需要大规模的碰撞来转移有威胁的近地物体
require a massive collision to deflect a threatening near-Earth object.
不过还有其它的建议提出
But other proposals suggest...
有可能会阻止世界末日
it may be possible to stop Armageddon...
只不过就是利用光束而已
with nothing more than a beam of light.
有几种方法来阻止世界末日
There are several ways to stop Armageddon.
有人建议出其不意的巨大撞击
Some propose a sudden massive impact...
实实在在地将近地小行星敲离轨道
that literally knocks an Earth-bound asteroid off course.
还有人提出任务的完成无需撞击
Others suggest the mission can be accomplished...
只要利用其它手段
without a collision by using other means...
诸如近距离核爆炸
such as a stand-off nuclear explosion...
将小行星推出威胁的轨道
to push the asteroid out of harm's way.
你在距离其表面很小距离的地方引爆核弹
You detonate the weapon some small distance off the surface.
其主要作用是为了让能量
The main effect then is for energy...
希望能以中子的形式 穿透其表面
hopefully in the form of neutrons, penetrating the surface.
你对其加热
And you heat it and you blow off pieces of the surface.
炸掉其表层
It's over a fairly large area...
这样你就减小了将其炸裂的机会
so you diminish the chance of breaking it up.
虽然还存在着一个问题
There's one problem, though.
核武器是被国际公约禁止在太空中使用
Nukes are banned from space by international treaty.
但要是小行星威胁到了我们的生存
But if an asteroid threatens our very survival...
还会有那么重要吗?
will that really matter?
就缓解策略而言
In terms of mitigation strategies...
我最具印象的就是使用核武器
I'm most impressed with the use of the nuclear weapons...
我认为它最有效
and l think it's the most efficient.
当然 这尚未试验过
Sure, it's not been tested...
但是除此之外 别无选择
but neither has anything else that we have.
此外 就从个人角度而言
And also, just from a personal standpoint...
我是宁愿偏离物体 而不愿牺牲北美
I would much rather deflect an object than sacrifice North America.
假如我随后不得不上法庭的话 那也无所谓
lf l had to go to court afterwards, that would be just fine with me.
但是你不必对小行星用核弹来推开它
But you don't have to nuke an asteroid in order to nudge it.
更安全的方法包括利用太阳帆
Safer methods include using solar sails.
这些在轨反射镜 据主张者称
These orbiting reflectors, according to advocates...
可以将太阳光聚焦到小行星上
could concentrate the Sun's rays on an asteroid.
产生的热量可以蒸发其表层
The heat generated would vaporize surface rock...
产生物质喷射
creating a jet of material that would propel the object...
推动物体远离近地轨道
away from an Earth-bound trajectory.
当然还有激光
Then there are lasers.
如果它们强大到足以切割最坚硬的金属
lf they're powerful enough to cut the strongest metal...
进行精细的手术
and perform delicate surgeries...
那么也许会有更加强大的版本来偏转小行星
then maybe a more powerful version could deflect an asteroid.
激光非常诱人 因为其比较经济
The laser is very attractive because it's more economical.
它基本上成本较低
It costs less, basically.
应用更加便当
It's easier to do.
它可以是机器人航天器
It could a robotic spacecraft.
激光利用光束射向小行星
The laser uses a beam of light to the asteroid...
把物质轰离小行星
which causes material to fly off from the asteroid...
并推动小行星
which then pushes the asteroid.
你不必携带东西上去
You don't have to carry the material up there...
就会对小行星施加推力
that's going to exert the force on the asteroid.
激光可以非常精准地定位
The laser can be very precisely directed.
可以循序渐进
It's very gradual.
可以在3个月里完成
It could be done over a three-month period.
研究人员在80年代
Researchers discovered a laser's potential...
偶然发现了激光的潜力
by accident in the eighties...
当时是在实验用短脉冲轰击硅晶片
while experimenting with short pulses on a wafer made of silicon...
这种材料类似于小行星的表面
material similar to the surface of an asteroid.
我们基本上准备了一架摄影机
We basically set up a movie camera...
与激光同步
and timed it with the laser...
这样我们就可以步进拍摄到
so we could take step-action shots of the material...
材料剥离硅片表面的镜头
leaving the surface of the silicon wafer.
我们对我们的发现感到震惊
And we were surprised to discover what we found.
就是 我们实际上看到了
That is, we could actually see...
这许多材料剥离了 看到它们蒸发了
these chunks of material coming off and see them vaporize.
它是科学发现 也是新的技术
It was a scientific discovery, as well as a new technology.
值得注意的是 那个发现
As significant as that discovery was...
还是从硅片到小行星的一大飞跃
it's still a big leap from a silicon wafer to an asteroid.
不过那可是难以做到的东西 支持者声称
But it's one that can be made, proponents claim...
激光束要比我们在地球上每天使用的
with a laser pulse 5,000 times more powerful...
强大上5000倍
than those we use every day on Earth.
这种超级激光 其动力来自目前的火箭和太阳能电池板
This super laser, powered by existing rockets and solar panels...
可以停泊在小行星的5公里远
could park as many as five kilometers away from an asteroid...
然后利用一系列短脉冲
then use a series of short pulses...
而不是用连续不断的脉冲 去偏离它
rather than a continuous one, to deflect it.
利用这种脉冲的原因
The reason for the pulse...
就在于极短的短脉冲可以传送足够的强度
is that the very short pulse can deliver enough intensity...
到小行星的表面
to the surface of the asteroid...
这样物质就可以被炸离小行星
so that the material explodes off from the asteroid.
一旦物质被炸离小行星
When that material explodes off from the asteroid,...
就会将小行星
it pushes the asteroid...
推向你所希望的方向
in the direction that you want to send it.
你同样需要极短的短脉冲
You also need the very short pulse...
因为随着激光束轰击小行星表面
because, as the laser pulse strikes the surface of the asteroid...
会从小行星上出现物质云
it creates a cloud of material that emerges from the asteroid.
物质云会吸收
That cloud of material...
射向小行星所有额外的光线
will absorb any additional light that's sent to the asteroid.
因此至关重要的是将所有的光能
So it's extremely important to get all of the light energy...
送入小行星的那个区域 要在极短的时间里
into that area of the asteroid in that very short time...
在乌云形成之前
before that black cloud forms.
对某些专家来说 激光甚至太阳帆是有效的
To some experts, lasers and even solar sails could work...
至少原则上是这样
at least in principle.
它们两者送出的强光
The intense light they both emit...
是可调节的 适合各类小行星
is adjustable and adaptable to all types of asteroids...
喷发出的物质 仅仅是尘埃
and the ejected material, mere puffs of dust...
不会对地球构成威胁
would pose no threat to Earth.
不过它们潜在的缺陷可能证明是可望不可及的
But their potential drawbacks could prove prohibitive.
将激光源或大型太阳镜保持在正确的位置上
Keeping the laser source or a large solar mirror...
是很难做到的
in the correct place is very difficult to do...
必须很长时间才能完成
and has to be done for a long time.
对于太阳反射
With regard to the solar reflection also...
还有吹出的尘埃的问题
then there's the question of the dust that's blown out.
将会对太阳镜有啥影响?
What is it going to do to the solar mirror?
因此这是个重大的长期问题
And so there are significant long-term problems.
因此将来能否做到 难说
And so whether that could be done in the future, we don't know.
目前
At the present time...
当然超出了我们的能力
it's certainly outside of our capability.
目前连续激光可产生更多的能量
There are continuous lasers now that produce more power...
25千瓦 50千瓦
25 kilowatts, 50 kilowatts...
已经用于军事目的
that have been made for military purposes...
能量超过了必需
that have more power than is necessary.
我们所提出的那种
The kind that we're proposing...
将需要采用超短脉冲激光
would require taking the ultra-short pulse lasers...
将能量提高到至少5千瓦
and increasing the power up to at least five kilowatts...
甚至10千瓦
maybe 10 kilowatts.
全力以赴或许在5到10年就可以做到
A focused effort could probably do this within five to ten years...
其实是可以做到的 只要下定决心
could actually be done if there was an intent to do so.
为什么就耽搁在一台激光器上呢?
And why stop at just one laser?
有朝一日 一队激光器
One day, a fleet of them...
将永久把守在地球周围
could be permanently stationed around Earth...
充当抵御威胁我们的小行星的保护盾
to act as a defensive shield against asteroids that threaten us.
我们会规避风险
We would avoid the danger...
利用最后的紧急起飞来解决问题
of having a last-minute scramble to solve the problem...
而不是发送核装置
than having to send up nuclear devices...
核武器到太空去 试图炸毁小行星
nuclear weapons into space, trying to blow up the asteroid...
那大概是个坏主意
which is probably a bad idea.
激光表现出小行星偏转器的潜能
Lasers show potential as asteroid deflectors...
但是还需要很长的时间才能作为切实可行的选择
but it will be a long time before they're a viable option.
在此之前 还有另一项缓解的提案
Until then, there's another mitigation proposal...
值得认真关注
that deserves serious attention.
那是两位前宇航员的发明
It's the brainchild of two former astronauts...
他们坚称这是阻止世界末日唯一可行的办法
who insist it's the only real way to stop Armageddon.
在所有阻止世界末日的主张里
Of all the proposals to stop Armageddon...
最有效的可能就是一个新玩艺
the most effective one...
叫做引力拖拉机
may be a contraption called a gravity tractor.
对于这么复杂的项目
For such a complicated undertaking...
其运作建立在一个非常简单的原理上
it operates on a very simple principle.
我们知道太空中的一切东西
We know that everything out there in space...
都具有引力
has a gravitational pull...
因此小行星自身就具有引力
so asteroids themselves have a gravitational pull.
我们同样知道飞船与小行星
And we also know that a spaceship...
相互之间有引力
interacts gravitationally with the asteroid.
因此如果飞船靠小行星足够近的话
So if the spaceship were to come close enough to the asteroid...
就会慢慢地将小行星拖离它的轨道
it could then begin to attract the asteroid slowly out of its course...
只要我们给予时间
if we can get it in time.
研发由B612基金组织
Developed by the B612 Foundation...
其名字来自
named after the asteroid...
文学经典《小王子》里的小行星
in the literary classic "The Little Prince"...
引力拖拉机正日益受到欢迎
the gravity tractor is gaining popularity...
应归功于其主要倡导者的努力
due to the efforts of its chief advocates...
两位前宇航员 卢杰和拉塞尔.施威卡特
two former astronauts, Ed Lu and Rusty Schweickart.
引力拖拉机是个弱偏转的概念
The gravity tractor is a very weak deflection concept...
然而却是非常精准的
but it's very precise.
我们不建议使用它
And so we don't recommend using it...
原因就在于我们所谓的主要偏转
for what we call the primary deflection...
也就是 让小行星错过地球
that is, to make the asteroid miss the Earth.
但是一旦你利用动能撞击这么做了
But once you've done that with a kinetic impact...
那是个非常不确定的调度
which is a very imprecise maneuver...
那么你就可以用上引力拖拉机
then you come in with a gravitational tractor...
对你已经完成的主要偏转
and you make a very precision adjustment...
进行非常精准的调整
on what you've done with the primary deflection.
引力拖拉机是
The gravity tractor's...
为数不多的小行星偏转手段之一
one of the very few asteroid deflection mechanisms...
不管怎样还是切实可行的
that is in any way realistic.
唯一两个目前看来切实可行的
The only two that are probably realistic right now...
就是动能撞击机
are kinetic impactor...
就是基本上你用飞船撞击小行星
where you just basically run into the asteroid with a spacecraft...
以及引力拖拉机
or the gravity tractor.
除了那两个
Apart from those two...
其余的大部分差不多都是科幻
most of the rest of those are pretty much science fiction.
主要利用现代技术
Using mostly existing technology...
动力为离子发动机和太阳能电池板的组合
and powered by a combination of ion engines and solar panels...
引力拖拉机自身的大小和重量相当于一辆高尔夫球车
the gravity tractor itself is about the size and weight of a golf cart.
按航天器标准并不很大
Not very large by spacecraft standards...
但是按其支持者的说法 它还是够大了
but it's still big enough, according to its proponents...
足以在动能撞击后完成任务
to finish the job after a kinetic impact.
这颗小行星围绕轴心旋转或翻滚 无论怎样
This asteroid is spinning around an axis or tumbling, whatever...
我都会用上引力拖拉机
and l come up with the gravity tractor...
我基本上就停泊在这里
and I basically park here.
我想把它往那个方向拉
I want to pull it in that direction.
因此不管事实上它是在翻滚
So in spite of the fact that it's tumbling...
我都不会去碰到它
I don't ever touch it.
我只是在它的前面拉它
I just pull up in front of it...
只要那是我想拉的方向
if that's the direction I want to pull it...
我就呆在那里 虽然它在翻滚
and l just stay there while it's tumbling.
比方说 如果小行星本身的直径是300英尺
Let's say if the asteroid itself is 300 feet in diameter...
那么我们就会徘徊在距离小行星重心
then we would want to hover something like 250 feet...
约250英尺的地方
from the center of gravity of that asteroid.
换句话说 就是在翻滚的小行星的
In other words, about 1 1/2 radiuses out...
1.5倍的半径处
from that tumbling asteroid.
我不会让小行星的重力将我拉过去
I don't let the gravity of the asteroid pull me in.
我必须发动我的离子引擎推进器
I have to fire my ion engine thrusters...
来保持距离 这样我就撞上它
off to the sides so l don't blast it.
这样一来 我就呆在那里
And by doing that, I stay right there...
一个星期 一个月 一年 不管多长时间
for a week, a month, a year, whatever it takes.
离子发动机可以应付很长很长的时间
Ion engines go for long, long periods of time.
好 因为我将无线电转发器装在
And now, because l have a radio transponder...
我的引力拖拉机上了 地球就可以非常精准地跟踪我
in my gravity tractor, the Earth can track me very precisely...
我准确地掌握轨道的变化
and I know exactly the change in the orbit...
我已经和小行星融为一体了
that I've made to the asteroid itself.
你在重塑太阳系
You're reshaping the solar system...
无需任何碰触
without ever touching anything.
那种掌控能力 精准移动
That ability to make controlled, precise movements...
是引力拖拉机的主要优点
is the gravity tractor's chief asset.
你需要做的就是确保
What you need to do is make sure that...
在偏转任何一颗小行星后
after you've deflected any asteroid...
它不会回来 稍后再来撞击你
that it doesn't come back and hit you at a later point.
引力拖拉机让你能做到
What a gravity tractor allows you to do...
精准地测量出它所要到的地方
is to measure precisely exactly where it's going...
对其进行微小的纠偏
and to make tiny corrections to it...
这样你完全可以肯定
so that you are very certain...
它将不会再回来撞上你了
that it is not going to come back and hit you.
尽管有这个优势 但是引力拖拉机的主要缺点
Despite this advantage, the gravity tractor's major drawback...
就是其拉力很小
is its very small force...
或许太小了 无法让较大的小行星产生变化
maybe too small to make a difference on a really big asteroid.
引力拖拉机需要较长的时间
The gravity tractor takes a long time...
对较小的小行星产生影响
and a small asteroid to be effective.
它或许必须要小于1公里
It would have to be much smaller than one kilometer...
或许是150米 300米
perhaps 150 meters, 300 meters.
阿波菲斯乃至更小的物体
Something the size of Apophis or smaller.
如果我们讨论的是需要对付较大的小行星
If we're talking about a need for a larger asteroid...
以及我们没有太多的时间来对付它
and we don't have as much time to devote to it...
那么引力拖拉机或许就不是可选的手段了
then gravity tractor is probably not the method of choice.
然而话又回到了期望时间
But it turns out that the expected time...
你发现可能会有小行星撞击与
between when you find that an asteroid impact is possible...
多少年后的实际撞击之间的预计时间
and when the actual impact is going to happen is many decades.
这样 大部分时间里 你有时间来使用这类东西
So, most of the time, you have time to use such a thing.
到我们遭遇那样大的物体打击时
By the time we get hit by something that big...
我们会用上的技术是我们现在无法想象的
we're going to have technology we can't even imagine now...
因此会有别的什么东西 而不是引力拖拉机
so there'll be something else and not the gravity tractor.
不过要是我们现在就必须去做的话 是能够做到的
But if we had to do it now, we could do it.
问题是我们现在就可以保护地球
The point is we can protect the Earth right now...
免遭小行星的撞击 只要我们尽力
from asteroid impacts if we do our work.
为了证明引力拖拉机的有效性
To demonstrate the gravity tractor's effectiveness...
B612基金组织瞄准了一项试验偏向
the B612 Foundation aims to perform a test deflection...
针对2015年的一颗非威胁小行星
on a non-threatening asteroid by the year 2015.
那是非常重要的 因为我们一旦发现有小行星
That's really important because if we find an asteroid...
非常接近于撞上地球
that's uncomfortably close to hitting the Earth...
你决定你必须去转移它
and you decide that you have to deflect it...
那就不是你测试飞行的好时机了
that's not a good time for your test flight.
你要事先做好测试飞行
You want the test flight to be done beforehand...
这样你就可以排除任何可能的错误
so you worked out any possible bugs.
实实在在的技巧去说服航天局
The real trick is convincing NASA...
它应当要演示这种能力
that it ought to demonstrate this capability...
然后才是我们最终不得不去使用它
before we end up having to use it.
那就是问题所在
That's the problem.
你涉及的或许就是数以百万计的生命啊
You're dealing with potentially millions of lives.
演示简单 成本低廉
It's simple and cheap to demonstrate it.
所以先要演示 才能知晓
So let's demonstrate it, and then we know.
这里来到了阻止世界末日的第三也是最后一步
This leads to the third and final step in stopping Armageddon.
谁来决定何时和如何去做
Who decides when and what to do...
要是有小行星已经非我们莫属了?
if an asteroid has our name on it?
有三个基本的步骤来阻止世界末日
There are three fundamental steps to stopping Armageddon.
甄别与缓解构成了前两个步骤
Detection and mitigation comprise the first two.
第三步或许是最具挑战的
The third and maybe most challenging one of all...
就是由谁来决定何时付之行动
is who makes the decision when to act.
现在 如果我们已经知道了将要发生的情况
Right now, if we knew something were coming...
我想极有可能是我们会仓狂出逃
I think it's likely that we would run around...
最后无所作为
and not do anything in time.
我认为重要的是基本上要有指南之类的东西
I think it's important to have, basically, sort of a manual.
小行星来了 我们怎么办?
When the asteroid comes, what do we do?
要回答这个问题迫切需要
Answering this question gains urgency...
更大更强的望远镜联网
as bigger and better telescopes come online...
诸如Pan STARRS 那是缩写
such as Pan-STARRS, an acronym...
即全景巡天望远镜和快速反应系统
for Panoramic Survey Telescope and Rapid Response System.
Pan STARRS是夏威夷大学的项目
Pan-STARRS is a University of Hawaii project...
有可能彻底改变近地物体的搜索
that may well revolutionize the search for near-Earth objects.
其概念是用大广角望远镜
The idea is to have a very wide field telescope...
具有超大广角的视野
with a huge field of view...
这样他们就可以看得更深 也就是更深入太空
so they can go deeper, that is, further out in space...
更快 更广泛地覆盖夜空
and do it faster and cover much more of the sky every night.
Pan STARRS之类的新程序
New programs like Pan-STARRS...
将会提高发现率
are going to increase the discovery rate.
因而一旦我们发现了这些物体中的绝大多数
And so once we find the vast majority of these objects...
我们就可以在未来100年里轻松跟踪它们
we can easily track them a hundred years into the future...
观察它们中的任何一个是否会成为问题
and see whether or not any of them are a problem.
一些专家预测 在未来的10到20年里
Some experts predict that within the next 10 to 20 years...
有多达百万个近地物体会被发现
as many as a million near-Earth objects could be discovered.
那除了我们已经发现的5000多个
That's in addition to the more than 5,000 we've already found.
即使是这样的指数增长
Even with this exponential increase...
还是会有太空物体 或许是彗星
it's still possible that a space object, perhaps a comet...
可能会漏网并打击我们
could evade detection and hit us.
彗星确实会出其不意地冒出
Comets can literally come out of the blue.
它们来自太阳系的外围
They come from the outer reaches of the solar system.
它们一旦出现 我们就有可能就只有几年功夫甚至还不到
And they come in, and we may only have a few years or less...
去着手某种偏转的努力
to mount some kind of a deflection effort.
因此我们不能确切知道有没有彗星直奔我们而来
So we don't know for sure that there's no comet heading our way.
不过彗星不会频繁光顾地球
But comets don't fly by the Earth very much...
因此我们非常自信
and so we have a very good confidence...
就是地球的主要威胁来自小行星
that the predominant Earth hazard is coming from asteroids.
有可能现在我们就会遭遇到小行星的打击
It is possible right now that we could be hit...
而我们却毫无察觉
by an asteroid that we're unaware of.
现在有大量的侦查在进行
There are plenty of surveys going on right now...
但是他们被安排
but they're geared for finding...
搜寻1公里以及更大的物体
the one kilometer and larger asteroids.
因此还有下至约150米的物体
And so there are objects down to about 150 meters...
是我们有为关心的
that we're particularly interested in...
我们只发现了其中的百分之几
and we've only found a few percent of those...
因此未来需要有更多的审视
so there needs to be much more surveying in the future...
去发现那些潜在的危险物体
to find those potentially hazardous objects.
现在 尚无协定
Right now, there are no protocols...
关于怎么做 何时做 以及谁来做决定
about what to do, when to act, and who makes these decisions...
万一即将发生天地大碰撞时
in the event of an imminent Earth impact.
那么谁拥有权力和能力
So who has the authority and the capability...
来保卫地球呢?
to protect the Earth?
航天局目前的宗旨是发现它们 跟踪它们
NASA's current charter is to find them, track them...
对它们进行物理描述
and physically characterize them.
它们的成分是什么? 如何将它们归类?
What are they made of? How are they put together?
他们还没有纲领去缓解它们
They don't yet have the charter to mitigate them.
你完全可以想象得出 小行星撞击
You can well imagine that an asteroid impact...
将会是个国际问题
would be an international problem...
因此那将会要某种国际合作
so it's going to take some international cooperation...
来决定谁做什么和何时去做
to decide who does what and when.
国际决定将非常缓慢
International decisions are extremely slow.
我认为重要的是召集国际会议
I think it's important that countries get together...
来讨论一个协定 就是你如何来做出这样的决定
and talk about a protocol for how you would make such a decision.
如果他们开始讨价还价 争论不休
And if they begin their quibbling and arguing...
在他们发现它的当口
at the moment they find it...
他们可能会一直讨价还价和争论下去
they may quibble and argue all of their time away...
直到不得不有所行动
before they have to do something.
好消息是这种想象
The good news is this conceivably...
可以将全世界人民统一到
could unify the people of the world...
围绕影响我们所有人的某些东西
around something that affects all of us.
我们可以共同努力去解决它
We could all work together to solve it.
全球都处于危险之中 不光是哪一个国家
The whole globe is at risk, not just any one country...
不光是太空大国
and not just space faring nations.
因此尽管太空大国
So while the space faring nations may end up...
最终责无旁贷
with the responsibility to do something...
那么谁又来为此买单呢?
who pays for it?
谁会说 你来!
Who says, "Do it"?
谁来承担债务呢?
Who handles the liability?
我们与联合国一道
We're working with the United Nations...
寄望他们作出迅速的决策
to get them prepared to make rapid decisions.
空间探索者协会
The Association of Space Explorers...
进入过太空的人的国际组织
an international organization of people who've flown in space...
将会在2009年向联合国提交提议
will submit recommendations for Earth impact preparedness...
为地球撞击做准备
to the United Nations in 2009.
这是第一步
It's a first step.
在此之前 让这些观点
Until then, let these views...
作为这个主题的最具权威的观点
serve as the best informed perspectives on the subject.
我们在这方面需要考虑的是
We need to think in terms of...
它关系到地球
this is something that's important for Earth...
关系到孩子
it's important for the children...
关系到我们的子孙后代
it's important for the people who come after us.
我们甘愿在此时就做好防范
And it's our willingness to prepare at this time...
给他们以工具
and to give them the tools...
这样如果以后威胁降临
so that should the threat emerge later on...
就会有资源 有能力
that there will be the resources, the ability...
有知识去解决那个威胁
and the knowledge to resolve that threat.
我们可能会有另一次通古斯
We may have another Tunguska...
一个能抹平整个都市的事件
an event that is capable of wiping out an entire city...
城市终结者
a city buster.
但是 在数以百万年计的范围里
However, on a scale of millions of years...
或许是5000万年
perhaps 50 million years...
我们有生命灭绝事件的可能性
we have the possibility of a life-extinguishing event.
明智之举就是现在就采取行动
It's prudent to take efforts today...
因为谁都不知道 下一次撞击何时降临
because no one knows when the next impact will come.
我们只知道它会降临
All we know is it's coming.
奇怪的是我并不担心
Strangely enough, I am not concerned...
不久的将来可能会发生的撞击
about a potential impact in the near future.
我知道概率 那是不可能的
I know the probabilities. It is unlikely.
但是同样不太可能的是 你坐上飞机 它会失事
But it's also unlikely that you will get on a plane and it will crash...
我们还是花大把的钱来保证飞机的安全
and we still spend lots of money making planes safe.
我们有各种方法来做到那一点
We have various ways of doing that.
对我来说 这几乎就是精算问题了
To me, this is almost an actuarial problem.
我们要确定威胁在哪里 如何去预防它
We're going to determine what the threat is and prevent it.